[
  {
    "question": "Which Earthworks artist frequently wraps monuments in fabric and worked closely with artist Jeanne-Claude?",
    "a": "Smithson",
    "b": "Christo",
    "c": "Turrell",
    "d": "Goldsworthy",
    "e": "Heizer",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Guerrilla Girls are based in the city of",
    "a": "New York",
    "b": "Paris",
    "c": "Boston",
    "d": "Seattle",
    "e": "London",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which architectural style did Philip Johnson pioneer?",
    "a": "International Style",
    "b": "Neoclassical",
    "c": "Classical",
    "d": "Art Nouveau",
    "e": "Contemporary",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which idea does the International Style of architecture follow when designing buildings?",
    "a": "Innovation is king.",
    "b": "Art reflects ideals.",
    "c": "Art is decorative.",
    "d": "Purpose follows design.",
    "e": "Form follows function.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A life-size terracotta army, along with horses and other equipment, was buried in the tomb of the emperor of the",
    "a": "Yuan Dynasty",
    "b": "Qin Dynasty",
    "c": "Han Dynasty",
    "d": "Tang Dynasty",
    "e": "Song Dynasty",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what purpose were traditional ink drawing scrolls from the Tang Dynasty created?",
    "a": "spreading propaganda",
    "b": "preaching Confucianism",
    "c": "promoting revolution",
    "d": "upholding tradition",
    "e": "inspiring contemplation",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What culture had a significant influence on traditional Indian images of Buddha?",
    "a": "Chinese",
    "b": "Japanese",
    "c": "Greek",
    "d": "Roman",
    "e": "Egyptian",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the Impressionist movement in Europe, Japan sent a group of artists to",
    "a": "the Netherlands",
    "b": "France",
    "c": "Spain",
    "d": "Britain",
    "e": "Portugal",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which part of Africa did the Nok civilization emerge?",
    "a": "North Africa",
    "b": "West Africa",
    "c": "South Africa",
    "d": "Central Africa",
    "e": "East Africa",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tribe settled the Benin Kingdom?",
    "a": "the Edo people",
    "b": "the Fang people",
    "c": "the Yoruba people",
    "d": "the Bwa people",
    "e": "the Igbo people",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did early Europeans traders and settlers coming to Africa often destroy African art?",
    "a": "They wanted to force Africans to assimilate to European traditions.",
    "b": "They wanted to harvest the valuable materials used to create the artwork.",
    "c": "They saw the artwork as dangerous pagan symbols.",
    "d": "They did not want the artwork to influence European art.",
    "e": "They needed to gain control over the tribes.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of art showed social stature in Polynesia?",
    "a": "textiles",
    "b": "sculpture",
    "c": "paintings",
    "d": "architecture",
    "e": "tattoos",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which area did Asmat tribal groups typically use huge carved wooden shields colored with black, red, and white during raids?",
    "a": "Micronesia",
    "b": "Australia",
    "c": "Melanesia",
    "d": "Polynesia",
    "e": "Indonesia",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which term describes the element in mosque architecture that faces towards Mecca?",
    "a": "dome",
    "b": "mihrab",
    "c": "minaret",
    "d": "qibla",
    "e": "minbar",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Native Americans in the Southwest lived in",
    "a": "pueblos",
    "b": "chickees",
    "c": "wigwams",
    "d": "tipis",
    "e": "longhouses",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following components are formal qualities of art EXCEPT",
    "a": "theme",
    "b": "form",
    "c": "shape",
    "d": "space",
    "e": "texture",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which line direction creates a feeling of peacefulness?",
    "a": "curved",
    "b": "diagonal",
    "c": "vertical",
    "d": "horizontal",
    "e": "zig-zag",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to shape, form is",
    "a": "three-dimensional",
    "b": "realistic",
    "c": "textured",
    "d": "multi-layered",
    "e": "two-dimensional",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of perspective takes atmospheric elements into account?",
    "a": "linear",
    "b": "aerial",
    "c": "isometric",
    "d": "simple",
    "e": "panoramic",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms refers to the name of a color?",
    "a": "saturation",
    "b": "intensity",
    "c": "value",
    "d": "contrast",
    "e": "hue",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who provided the underlying concepts that led to the development of the color wheel?",
    "a": "Vincent van Gogh",
    "b": "Leonardo da Vinci",
    "c": "Aristotle",
    "d": "Isaac Newton",
    "e": "Pablo Picasso",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term “local color” refers to",
    "a": "the effect that special lighting has on an object",
    "b": "color contrast between one object and another",
    "c": "the hue of an object under harsh lighting",
    "d": "colors chosen for their emotional impact",
    "e": "the true color of an object in normal daylight",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Greeks, where do the corners of the eyes fall?",
    "a": "halfway between the chin and the top of the ears",
    "b": "halfway between the chin and the middle of the scalp",
    "c": "halfway between the chin and the top of the head",
    "d": "halfway between the chin and the middle of the nose",
    "e": "halfway between the chin and the brow line",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which form of balance employs objects that are slightly differentiated on each side of the axis?",
    "a": "transitional balance",
    "b": "approximate symmetry",
    "c": "radial symmetry",
    "d": "asymmetrical balance",
    "e": "symmetrical balance",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which formal quality of art refers to the dimensional relations within an artwork?",
    "a": "form",
    "b": "composition",
    "c": "rhythm",
    "d": "space",
    "e": "scale",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element is repeated to form a pattern?",
    "a": "rhythm",
    "b": "theme",
    "c": "contrast",
    "d": "motif",
    "e": "texture",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of color has experienced the GREATEST increase in popularity since the twentieth and twenty-first centuries?",
    "a": "symbolic",
    "b": "optical",
    "c": "local",
    "d": "arbitrary",
    "e": "expressive",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Intensity refers to the",
    "a": "balance between two colors",
    "b": "lightness or darkness of a color",
    "c": "name of a color",
    "d": "brightness or purity of a color",
    "e": "emotional impact of a color",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Freeform and irregular shapes and forms are MOST often referred to as",
    "a": "fluid",
    "b": "abstract",
    "c": "organic",
    "d": "dynamic",
    "e": "amorphous",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to a sculpture that projects only slightly from its surface?",
    "a": "flat art",
    "b": "fresco secco",
    "c": "plain sculpture",
    "d": "minimal projection",
    "e": "bas relief",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  }
]